Guide to the Gorham Munson Papers on the American Social Credit Movement and New Democracy, 1899 - 1969, bulk 1932 - 1945
Gorham Munson Papers on the American Social Credit Movement and New Democracy, 1899 - 1969, bulk 1932 - 1945
- Pamphlets
  - Fletcher, Joseph Frances. The Church and Social Credit. New York: National Council, Dept. of Christian Social Service, 1934. 8 pp.
  - Grandy, Owen. National Dividends Without Taxation, a Sane Plan for Sound Money. By a Country Banker. Churubusco, Indiana: Riverside Press, 1935. 43 pp.
  - Gordon-Cumming, Michael. Introduction to Social Credit. 6th ed. London: C. W. Daniel Co., 1935. 40 pp.
  - Halldorson, Salome. Debt-and-Tax Finance Must Go. Winnipeg, 1943. 51 pp.
  - Hargrave, John. Social Credit Clearly Explained; 101 Questions Answered. London: SCP Publishing House, 1945. 67 pp.
  - Hattersley, Charles Marshall. Aberhart and Alberta, the First Phase. London: Published for the York Social Credit Conference Liaison Committee, 1938. 43 pp. 2 copies.
  - Hattersley, Charles Marshall. Men, Machines and Money: the Problem of the Machine Age and its Solution. 3d ed. Mexborough, Yorks: Times Printing Co., 1932, 48 pp. 2 copies.
  - Hattersley, Charles Marshall. Now, or Never? Financial Principles in Relation to Present Requirements: a Survey, with Certain Proposals. Swinton, Mexborough, Yorks: S.C.C.C., 1942. 32 pp.
  - Hayek, Friedrich August von. Freedom and the Economic System. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1939. 37 pp.
  - Hickling, George. Social Debt or Social Credit. London: Social Credit Press, 1937. 19 pp.
  - Hogan, John. Banner Unfurled. Auckland,: New Zealand Social credit Movement? 1940? 42 pp.
  - Jeffery, R. L., and Thrane, F. W. The Signal is Green. Seattle, 1938. 48 pp. Mimeographed.
  - Johnson, Hewlett. Social Credit and the War on Poverty. London: Stanley Nott, 1936. 31 pp.
  - Joseph, Arthur Wolfe. The A + B Theorem. London: Nevi Age Press, 1935? 19 pp.
  - Kelly, Vincent. Blood Money: A Startling Exposure of the Traffic in Arms. Sydney: Commercial Printing Co., 1935? 40 pp.
  - Kelly, Vincent. The Money Spider's Web. Sydney: Commercial Printing Co., 1935? 40 pp.
  - Kitson, Arthur. A Letter to H.R.H. the Prince of Wales on the World Crisis--its Cause, and Remedy. Oxford: Alden Press, 1931. 30 pp.
  - Knowles, John. Social Credit and Christian Ideals. London: Figurehead. Printed by G. Stevens & Co., 1935. 77 pp.
  - Lane, Jeremy. Money Enough. New York: New Economics Press, 193-? 32 pp. 3 copies.
  - Larkin, James Crate. From Debt to Prosperity: An Introduction to the Proposals of Social Credit. New York: New Economics Press, 1934? 62 pp.
  - Larkin, James Crate. From Debt to Prosperity: The Proposals of Social Credit. 2d ed., rev. and enl. New York: New Economics Press, 1935? 82 pp.
  - Levesque, Georges-Henri. Social Credit arid Catholicism. Ottawa: College Dominicain, 1936. 25 pp.
  - M., H. M. The A + B Theorem. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 35 pp. 2 copies.
  - M., H. M. An Outline of Social Credit. Foreword by Major C. H. Douglas. London: Credit Research Library, 1929. 52 pp.
  - Mack, Harold L. Something for Nothing. Carmel-by-the-Sea, Cal.: Carmel Press, 1936. 59 pp.
  - McLaren, John. Recovery Through a Townsend Pension... Financed Through a Social Credit... Boston: Century Press, 1935? 24 pp.
  - Marx, Karl. The Communist Manifesto. Authorized English translation, edited and annotated by Friedrich Engels. New York: International Publishers, 1935. 47 pp.
  - Moor, Frewan. Debts Make War and Work. Ottawa, 1938. 20 pp.
  - Muir, Edwin. Social Credit and the Labour Party: An Appeal. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 28 pp.
  - New Economics Group of New York. Financial Freedom for Americans: an Open Letter to American Citizens from the Committee of Correspondence of the New Economics Group of New York. New York, 193-? 16 pp. 2 copies.
  - New Economics Group of New York. The Social Credit Proposal; Economic Security with Freedom. New York, 194-? 27 pp.
  - New Economics Group of New York. What is Social Credit? The Basis for Absolute Economic Security. New York, 193-? 19 pp.
  - Nichols, Herbert Edward. Alberta's Fight for Freedom. Edmonton: Alberta Social Credit League, 1963. 5 parts, 107 pp.
  - Nichols, Herbert Edward. A Handbook of Social Credit. Edmonton: Social Credit Association of Canada, 1952? 134 pp.
  - Official Report Alberta: A Documented Record of Mr. John Hargrave's Visit to the Province of Alberta, Canada, December 8, 1936 to January 25, 1937, Incorporating a Review of His Activities as Honorary Social Credit Adviser to the Alberta Government Planning Committee. London: Social Credit Party of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, 1937. 48 pp.
  - Overholser, Willis A. A Short Review and Analysis of the History of Money in the United States, with an Introduction to the Current Money Problem. Libertyville, Ill.: Progress Publishing Concern, 1936. 61 pp.
  - Pound, Ezra Loomis. Alfred Venison's Poems: Social Credit Themes, by the Poet of Titchfield Street. 2nd Impression. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 32 pp.
  - Pound, Ezra Loomis. Social Credit: An Impact. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 31 pp.
  - Protocols of the Wise Men of Zion. Protocols of the Learned Elders of Zion. Translated from the Russian text by Victor E. Marsden. London: Britons Publishing Society, 1933. 75 pp.
  - Rhys, W. H. Douglas Social Credit and the Individual. Melbourne: Social Credit Press, 1936. 19 pp.
  - Rhys, W. H. Real Wealth and Financial Poverty: a Synopsis of the Douglas Social Credit Proposals. final ed. Melbourne: Social Credit Press, 1932. 68 pp.
  - Riedel, C. G. The Goldsborough Money Reform Bill. Hawthorne, Cal.: Omni Publications, 1953. 31 pp.
  - Roberts, H. Neville. The Fruits of Freedom: a New Ireland Through Economic Nationalism. Dublin: Talbot Press, 193-? 32 pp.
  - Rynne, Stephen. The Flight from our Country (31,436 Souls in 1937) Being Letters between Stephen Rynne, a Farmer, and Thomas Kennedy, a Townsman, on the Cure for Rural Depopulation. Dublin, 1938? 24 pp.
  - Scrutton, Robert J. A Plan of National Action for the Prosperity Campaign. Coventry, 1933. 22 pp. 3 copies.
  - Scrutton, Robert J. Prosperity Campaign, Towards Social Credit and Christian Values and a Healthy Order of Society. Coventry, 193-? 23 pp. 2 copies.
  - Secor, Delmar L., ed. The Opposite of Socialism. West De Pere, Wis.: Delsec Co., 1936. 134 pp.
  - Security Without Debt or Taxation: an Engineer-Economist's Commentary on a Secure Social Order. Port Elizabeth, South Africa, 1943. 44 pp.
  - Serra, Walter Gauther Comte. Economies? Devaluation? or What? Alternative Proposal to the Fallacies of Major Grogan and the Economic Development Committee. Nairobi?: W. Boyd & Co., 1934? 44 pp. 2 copies.
  - Serra, Walter Gauther Comte. The Social Credit Proposals, Draft Scheme for Kenya. Nairobi: W. Boyd & Co., 1934? 26 pp.
  - Simpson, Samuel Wilson. Prosperity by Freedom and Democracy: an Open Letter to the President of the United States of America. New York, 1934. 51 pp. 2 copies.
  - Social Credit Co-ordinating Committee. Employment After the War: a Memorandum Submitted by the Social Credit Co-ordinating Committee for the Consideration of Sir William Beveridge. 2d ed. Mexborough, Yorks: S.C.C.C., 194-? 12 pp.
  - Social Credit Co-ordinating Centre. Social Credit in the Post-War World: Report of the Conference Called by the Social Credit Co-ordinating Centre and Held at Oxley Hall, Leeds, April, 1948. Nottingham, 1948? 62 pp.
  - Spear, Ben. Lincoln Legal Tender Money. Spokane, Wash., 1934. 100 pp.
  - Stabler, Charles Norman. The Financial Section of a Newspaper. College edition. New York: Herald Tribune, 1935. 66 pp.
  - Stones, William. What Road, Australia? Sydney, 1949? 48 pp.
  - Symons, W. T., and Tait, Fred. The Just Price. A Financial Policy for the Independent Labour Party, with Summary of Proposals and Criticism of the Finance Enquiry Committee Reports. Leicester, England: Blackfriars Press; 1926. 35 pp.
  - Tait, Fred. The Douglas Theory and its Communal Implications. Gateshead-on-Tyne: Stephen H. Wilson, 192-? 20 pp.
  - Thompson, Hall. Peering Faces. Brisbane: International Publishing Co., 1936. 75 pp.
  - Thompson, Robert N. Canadians ... It's Time you Knew! 2d ed. Ottawa: Aavangen Press, 1961. 98 pp.
  - Towne, Elizabeth Jones. Democracy's Dividends: $5 Weekly to Every Citizen from Birth to Death and How to Have Them. Holyoke, Mass., 1935? 32 pp.
  - Tresckow, Walter von. Merchants of Debt: a Study in the Changing Character of American Banking and its Effect on Securities. New York: Young & Ottley, 1936. 54 pp.
  - Tutte, William A. Economic Madness and the Path to Sanity: an Outline of Douglas Social Credit. Vancouver, B.C., 1934. 35 pp.
  - Vickers, Vincent Cartwright. Finance in the Melting Pot: Reform or Revolution? The Petition to His Majesty the King. London: Stanley Nott, 1936. 31 pp.
  - Ward, William. The Abolition of Poverty and the Disappearance of Unemployment and War: a Message of Hope... London: Dingle's Printers, 1934?
  - Ward, William. The National Dividend: the Instrument for the Abolition of Poverty. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 48 pp.
  - Young & Ottley, Inc., New York. The Present Business Cycle and Outlook as of March 12, 1932; Part I, The Unfavorable Factors. New York, 1932. 26 pp.
- American Social Credit Movement Emblem
  - Emblem, 15 inches x 18 inches (Box 34)
    A woodsman striking at the roots of a tree with lettering, American Social Credit Movement, green on white, wood.
- Scrapbooks
  Contain clippings on Social Credit news and related matters. The items are not ordered nor are particular scrapbooks limited to subjects. Complete inventory of scrapbooks is available as a PDF: http://www.wesleyan.edu/libr/schome/FAs/munson_scrapbooks.pdf
  - 11 scrapbooks (Box 35-38)
- Periodicals
  Social Credit periodicals from Australia, Canada, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom, and the United States. A total of 43 periodicals, short to full runs.
  - Abundance (Glasgow, Great Britain), volumes 1-4, 1939-1946 (Box 39-49)
  - The Adelphi (Manchester, England), volumes 3-7, 13, 1931-1933, 1936
  - Alberta Social Credit Chronicle (Alberta, Canada), volumes 1-4, 1934-1938
  - The Albertan (Alberta, Canada), volumes 36, 37, 1937-1938
  - Attack! (London, England), number 10-42, 1933-?
  - The Beacon (Winnipeg, Canada), volumes 1-3, 1937-1939
  - Christendom (Oxford, England), volumes 5-8, 1935-1938
  - Controversy (Carmel, California), volumes 1-4, 1934-1935
  - The Douglas Review (Toronto, Canada), volumes 1, 2, 1934
  - Douglas Social Credit (Toronto, Canada), volumes 1, 1935, 1936
  - The Douglas Social Credit Advocate (Alberta, Canada), volumes 1, 2, 1934-1936
  - Dynamic America (New York, NY, USA), 1938-1942
  - Economic Forum (Concord, NH, USA), volumes 1-4, 1933-1937
  - The Emancipator (Georgetown, TX, USA), 1940-1952
  - Everyman (London, England), volumes 6, 7, 1932
  - Farming First (Auckland, New Zealand), volumes 9, 10, 12, 1935, 1937
  - G. K.'s Weekly (London, England), volume 17, 1933
  - The Key to Economic Democracy (Wellington, New Zealand), volume 1, 2, 1935, 1936
  - Men First (New York, NY, USA), numbers 1-147, 1940-1943
  - Message from Hargrave (London, England), numbers 2-536
  - Money (New York, NY, USA), volumes 2-7, 1937-1943
  - The New Age (London, England), volumes 49-61, 1931-1937
  - Now Britain (London, England), volume 1, 1933
  - New Democracy (New York, NY, USA), volumes 1-6, 1933-1936
  - The New Economics (Melbourne, Australia), New Series numbers 39-99, 1933-1936
  - New Democracy (New York, NY, USA), volumes 1-6, 1933-1936
  - The New English Weekly (London, England), volumes 1-31, 1932-1947
  - The New Era (Sydney, Australia), volumes 28-35, 1939-1941
  - New Leader (New York, NY, USA), volumes 12-?, 1932-?
  - New Times (Melbourne, Australia), volumes 1-3, 1935-1937
  - Parliament Christian (London, England), volumes 1, 2, 1940-1942
  - Prosperity (Coventry, England), I./volumes 1-4, 1932-1936. II./volume 2, 1938, 1939
  - Purpose (London, England), volumes 5, 8-12, 1933, 1936-1940
  - Reality (Melbourne, Australia), volumes 1-3, 1935-1937
  - Rebel (Calgary, Canada), volumes 1-2, 1937-1938
  - Security (Toronto, Canada), 1936-1937
  - Social Credit (London, England), volumes 1-10, 1934-1939
  - Social Credit News (Johannesburg), volumes 1, 1935
  - Social Credit Review of East Africa (Nairobi), volumes 1-2, 1936-1937
  - The Social Crediter (Liverpool, England), volumes 1-5, 1938-1940
  - The United Farmer (Calgary, Canada), volumes 15, 1935
  - Voice of Ulster (Belfast, Great Britain)
  - Health (London, England), volumes 1-2, 1937-1939
  - Why? (Auckland, New Zealand), volumes 1-6, 1934-1937
- Books
  Munson's books on Social Credit and related economic subjects. Books are shelved separately from the rest of the collection.
  - Ayres, Clarence Edwin. The Theory of Economic Progress. Chapel Hill: Univ. of North Carolina Press, 1944. 317 pp.
  - Beer, Max. The Life and Teaching of Karl Marx. Translated by T. C. Partington and H. J. Stenning, and revised by the author. London: Parsons, 1925. 148 pp.
  - Bjorset, Brynjolf. Distribute or Destroy! A Survey of the World's Glut of Goods with a Description of Various Proposals and Practical Experiments for its Distribution. London: S. Nott, 1936. 188 pp.
  - Brandeis, Louis Dembitz. Other People's Money, and How the Bankers Use It. Washington: National Home Library Foundation, 1933. 152 pp.
  - Butchart, Montgomery, comp. Money: Selected Passages Presenting the Concepts of Money in the English Tradition, 1640-1935. London: S. Nott, 348 pp.
  - Calverton, Victor Francis, ed. The Making of Society: An Outline of Sociology. New York: Modern Library, 1937. 923 pp.
  - Chase, Stuart. Goals for America: A Budget of our Needs and Resources. New York: Twentieth Century Fund, 1942. 134 pp.
  - Chase, Stuart. The Road We are Traveling, 1914-1942. New York: Twentieth Century Fund, 1942. 106 pp.
  - Chase, Stuart. Where's the Money Coming From? Problems of Postwar Finance. New York: Twentieth Century Fund, 1943. 179 pp.
  - Chastenet, J. L. The Bankers' Republic. Translated by C. H. Douglas. London: C. Palmer, 1926. 202 pp.
  - Colbourne, Maurice Dale. Charles the King: A Chronicle Play. London: S. French, 1937. 122 pp.
  - Colbourne, Maurice Dale. Charles the King: A Chronicle Play. London: Figurehead, 1937. 144 pp.
  - Colbourne, Maurice Dale. Economic Nationalism. London: Figurehead, 1933. 284 pp.
  - Colbourne, Maurice Dale. Unemployment or War. New York: Coward-McCann, Inc., 1928. 307 pp.
  - Cole, George Douglas Howard, ed. What Everybody Wants to Know About Money. A Planned Outline of Monetary Problems by Nine Economists from Oxford. New York: A. A. Knopf, 1939. 435 pp.
  - Curtiss, John Shelton. An Appraisal of the Protocols of Zion. New York: Columbia University Press, 1942. 117 pp.
  - Demant, Vigo Auguste, ed. The Just Price. An Outline of the Mediaeval Doctrine and an Examination of Its possible Equivalent To-Day. Essays Contributed to the Research Work of the Christian Social Council. London: Student Christian Movement Press, 1930. 151 pp.
  - Demant, Vigo Auguste, ed. This Unemployment: Disaster or Opportunity? An Argument in Economic Philosophy. London: Student Christian Movement Press, 1932. 157 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Alberta Experiment: An Interim Survey. London: Eyre and Spottiswoods, 1937.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Control and Distribution of Production. London: C. Palmer, 1922. 175 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Credit-Power and Democracy. With a Draft Scheme for the Mining Industry. 4th ed. London: S. Nott, 1934. 211 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Douglas Manual. Being a Recension of Passages from the Works of Major C. H. Douglas Outlining Social Credit. Compiled by Philip Mairet. New York: Coward McCann, 1934. 116 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Economic Democracy. London: C. Palmer, 1928. 154 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Evidence before the Select Standing Committee on Banking and Commerce on Bill No. 83, an Act Respecting Banks and Banking, and on the resolution of Mr. Irvine, M.P., re the business, function and control of financial credit. Canada, House of Commons, March 8, 1923. London: Credit Research Library, 1923.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Major C. H. Douglas Speaks. Sydney, N.S.W.: Douglas Social Credit Association, 1933. 101 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. The Monopoly of Credit. London: Chapman & Hall, 1931. 128 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Social Credit. New York: W. W. Norton & Company, 1933. 212 pp.
  - Douglas, Clifford Hugh. Warning Democracy. London: C. M. Grieve, 1931. 207 pp.
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lansing. The Bank for International Settlements at Work. New York: Macmillan, 1932. 631 pp.
  - Dyson, William Henry. Artist Among the Bankers. New York: E. P. Dutton & Co., 1934. 244 pp.
  - Greenwood, Samuel. Prosperity, No Employment. Blackburn: The Times Printing Works, 1935. 176 pp.
  - Hale, Annie Riley. A School Ma'am Looks at Money. Pasadena, Calif.: San Pasqual Press, 1940. 155 pp.
  - Hansen, Alvin Harvey. Full Recovery or Stagnation? New York: Norton, 1938. 350 pp.
  - Hargrave, John. The Confession of the Kibbo Kift. A declaration and general exposition of the work of the Kindred. London: Duckworth, 1927. 342 pp.
  - Hargrave, John. Montagu Norman. New York: Greystone Press,c1942. 239 pp.
  - Hattersley, Charles Marshall. This Age of Plenty: Its Problems and Their Solution. 4th ed. London: I. Pitman, 1933. 427 pp.
  - Hayek, Friedrich August von. The Road to Serfdom. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1945. 250 pp.
  - Hiskett, William Robert and Franklin, J. A. Searchlight on Social Credit. London: P. S. King & Son, 1939. 173 pp.
  - Holter, Elizabeth Sage. The ABC of Social Credit. New York: Coward, McCann, 1934.
  - Honest Money Year Book and Directory, 1940. Edited by the National Monetary Conference. Chicago, Ill.: Honest Money Founders, Inc., 1939-
  - Howe, Robert Harrison. The Evolution of Banking: A Study of the Development of the Credit System. Chicago: C. H. Kerr & Company, 1915. 192 pp.
  - Johnson, Dallas Devello. Consume! The Monetary Radical's Defense of Capitalism. New York: Dynamic America Press, 1940. 120 pp.
  - Jones, Tudor J. You and Parliament. London: Figurehead, 1935. 76 pp.
  - Keynes, John Maynard. The Economic Consequences of the Peace. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Howe, 1920. 298 pp.
  - Kidd, Benjamin. The Science of Power. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1918. 318 pp.
  - Kitson, Arthur. The Bankers' Conspiracy! Which Started the World Crisis. London: E. Stock, 1933. 102 pp.
  - Mallon, Guy Ward. Bankers vs. Consumers. New York: The John Day Company, 1933. 139 pp.
  - Mitchell, John. Tax-Bonds or Bondage and the Answer to Federal Union. Liverpool: K.R.P. Publications, 1940. 94 pp.
  - Moulton, Harold Glenn. The Financial Organization of Society. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1921. 789 pp.
  - Munson, Gorham Bert. Aladdin's Lamp: the Wealth of the American People. New York: Creative Age Press, 1945. 420 pp.
  - Munson, Gorham Bert. The Psychology of Plenty. New York: Practical Psychology Monthly, 1937. 73 pp.
  - Myers, Margaret Good. Monetary Proposals for Social Reform. New York: Columbia University Press, 1940. 191 pp.
  - Nordskog, Andrae B. Spiking the Gold: or, Who Caused the Depression, and the Way Out. Los Angeles, Calif.: Gridiron Publishing Co., 1932. 122 pp.
  - Reckitt, Maurice Benington. As it Happened: An Autobiography. London: J. M. Dent, 1941. 306 pp.
  - Reckitt, Maurice Benington. A Christian Sociology for To-day: an Abridged Edition of Faith and Society. London and New York: Longmans, Green and Co., 1934. 286 pp.
  - Reeve, Joseph Edwin. Monetary Reform Movements: A Survey of Recent Plans and Panaceas. Washington: American Council on Public Affairs, 1943. 404 pp.
  - Rose, William. Social Credit Handbook. Toronto and Montreal: McClelland and Stewart, 1968. 154 pp.
  - Scrutton, Robert J. A People's Runnymede. London, A. Dakers Limited, 1941. 200 pp.
  - Serra, Walter Gauther, Comte. Property: Its Substance and Value. Translated by T. V. Holmes. Preface by the Dean of Canterbury. London: Figurehead, 1935. 84 pp.
  - Social Credit Pamphleteer. By various hands. Pamphlets on the New Economics. London: Stanley Nott, 1935. 10 no. in 1 v.
  - Soddy, Frederick. Wealth, Virtual Wealth and Debt: the Solution of the Economic Paradox. 2d ed. New York: E. P. Dutton & Co., 1933. 820 pp.
  - Stevens, John Austin. Albert Gallatin. Boston and New York: Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1899. 419 pp.
  - Symons, W. T. The Coming of Community. London: Daniel, 1931. 330 pp.
  - Voorhis, Horace Jeremiah. Out of Debt, Out of Danger: Proposals for War Finance and Tomorrow's Money. New York: Devin-Adair Company, 1943. 238 pp.
  - Walter Weyl: An Appreciation. Philadelphia: Private Print., 1922. 160 pp.
  - Walters, Raymond. Albert Gallatin: Jeffersonian Financier and Diplomat. New York: Macmillan, 1957. 461 pp.
  - Williams, John Henry. Postwar Monetary Plans, and Other Essays. New York: A. A. Knopf, 1944. 297 pp.
  - Wilson, Robert McNair. Monarchy or Money Power. 2d Rev. and Enl. Ed. London: Eyre and Spottiswoode, 1934 272 pp.
  - Winslow, Floyd Truman and Brougham, Bruce. Money and Its Power. Washington, D. C.: National Home Library Foundation, 1935. 85 pp.